There are some sounds most of us acknowledge are irritating – the crunching of crisps, the humming of the air conditioning or a screaming baby.
我们大多数人都认同，有些声音确实很刺耳——比如咀嚼薯片的嘎吱声、空调的嗡嗡声，或是婴儿的哭闹声。
These noises, for many people, act as a mere inconvenience that can distract us from the task at hand.
对很多人来说，这些噪音只是小麻烦，会让我们分心，无法专注于手头的事情。
However, there are some amongst us who have a much more severe response to these noises.
但有些人对这类声音的反应要剧烈得多。
The question we ask today is: has a noise ever made you feel so angry that you could explode with rage?
今天我们要探讨的问题是：你是否曾因为某个声音而愤怒到近乎抓狂？
If the answer is yes, you may be suffering from misophonia.
如果答案是肯定的，那你可能患上了恐音症。
The word ‘misophonia’ literally means ‘a hatred of sound’ and is sometimes called Selective Sound Sensitivity Syndrome.
“恐音症”这个词的字面意思就是“对声音的厌恶”，它有时也被称为选择性声音敏感综合征。
There are some experts who doubt the existence of the condition. However, for those who claim to suffer from it, the experience can be traumatic.
有些专家怀疑这种病症是否真的存在，但对那些自称患有恐音症的人来说，这种体验是极具创伤性的。
Certain sounds trigger intense emotional or psychological responses that may seem over the top compared with a non-sufferer’s complaints.
某些特定声音会引发他们强烈的情绪或心理反应，相较于非患者的不满，这种反应显得有些过分夸张。
The sound of a loved one chewing their food could trigger a sufferer’s anxiety levels, or cause them to panic.
挚爱之人咀嚼食物的声音，都可能让恐音症患者的焦虑感飙升，甚至引发恐慌。
It may even activate their fight-or-flight reflexes, making them want to flee.
这种声音甚至会激活他们的“战斗或逃跑”本能，让他们想要立刻逃离。
In extreme cases, that feeling of panic may result in intense bouts of fury and end up with sufferers going berserk.
在极端情况下，这种恐慌感会转化为一阵阵暴怒，最终导致患者情绪失控、行为失常。
Sadly, there’s no known cure.
遗憾的是，目前恐音症尚无方法可以治疗。
Tinnitus retraining therapy, which helps people tolerate noises, may aid sufferers, while cognitive behavioural therapy and counselling could also help people manage the condition.
能帮助人们耐受噪音的耳鸣再训练疗法或许能为患者提供帮助，认知行为疗法和心理咨询也有助于患者控制病情。
According to James Cartreine, a clinical psychiatrist, the condition can lead to isolation.
临床精神病学家詹姆斯·卡特赖恩表示，恐音症可能会导致患者与世隔绝。
Sufferers use coping strategies that include avoiding places with lots of noises, like restaurants, or moving away when they feel like lashing out at someone due to their breathing.
患者会采取各种应对策略，比如避开餐厅这类噪音密集的场所，或是当别人的呼吸声让他们忍不住想要发作时，选择立刻走开。
So, the next time you see someone fly into a rage because of a sound that is driving them crazy, it may be due to a difficult condition they are trying to manage, and not just because they loathe a certain sound.
所以下次当你看到有人因为某个声音而勃然大怒、几近崩溃时，这可能并非因为他们单纯讨厌那种声音，而是因为他们正在艰难地应对一种病症。